



# PERSONAL PROFILE

A digital marketer with hands-on experience in all levels of campaign implementation, including performance tracking, SEO, SEM, web design, automated marketing systems, email marketing, and lasting user experiences. I have over 5 years of digital marketing experience and I often work for several clients on several projects simultaneously.

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Web marketing, digital asset creation
- Wordpress, PHP and multisite experience
- Salesforce and Pardot admin (Automated sales and marketing systems)
- Working knowledge of Google AdWords, Analytics, MyBusiness and other SEO tools.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## DIGITAL MARKETING STRATEGIST

Trucks & Parts | 2019 - 2020

### INTERNET MARKETING SPECIALIST

Club Z! Tutoring | 2018 - 2019

# CONTENT MARKETING ASSISTANT

University of Florida CJC | Aug - Dec 2018

## SEO COPYWRITER AND EDITOR

LawnPartsPro | 2016 - 2018

### MARKETING ASSOCIATE

Ultra Clean Systems | 2014 - 2015

# **VOLUNTEER PROJECTS**

## TAMPA BAY WATCH

Digital Marketing and SEO audit (2018)

### RAMMP RESTAURANT GROUP

Digital Marketing and SEO audit (2018)

## MOSI

Admin Volunteer (2014)

# **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: 954-235-0191 blackjosephryan@gmail.com www.ryanjblack.io Seminole Heights in Tampa, FL 33610

# **EDUCATION HISTORY**

### M.A.M.C IN WEB DESIGN

University of Florida | 2018

## **B.A. IN JOURNALISM**

University of South Florida | 2015

# SKILLS / INTERESTS

- Multimedia creation (Adobe suite)
- Wordpress development, design and admin
- -HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, PHP
- MAMP Pro, Atom, Git, GitHub
- Technical writing and copy editing